Dustin J Bayham BA, MS, LPC

https://dbayham.github.io/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/dustin-bayham-20520865

Software Developer

Master of Science level of education with approximately 10+ years of professional experience working within the field of healthcare and lifelong learner who has an innate interest in the study of human behavior, information technology, cybersecurity, and ethical hacking.

TECHNICAL INVENTORY

Java • Python • HCL • Bash Scripting • AWS • Spring • Hibernate • JPA • JavaScript • MVC • HTML • CSS • Flexbox • Grid • TDD • Terraform • Agile (Scrum) • Object Oriented Programming (OOP) • AJAX • JSON • Restful APIs • Responsive Design / Mobile • Structured Query Language (SQL) • Relational Databases • Source Control / Git • Kali Linux

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE & PROJECTS

We Can Code IT, Columbus, OH
Software Development – Full Stack Java 2021

Planned, designed, and developed professionally programmed applications in collaborative team-based and independent settings.

Virtual Pet: Tamagotchi-style console application

Java, IntelliJ, Git, Github, GitBash, TDD, OOP

SneakerGeek Review Site: product review site utilizing dynamic pages.

Spring MVC, IntelliJ, CSS, Git, Github, POJO, HTML, Thymeleaf

Botnet Maker 1.0 – a click counter based game utilizing JavaScript function.

JavaScript, Java, IntelliJ, VSCode & CSS, Git, Github, HTML

Teacher-Tools: a hybrid multi-page Saas application aimed to enable the teacher to manage their classroom

Java, Spring MVC (Thymeleaf), CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Github

WORK EXPERIENCE

JPMorgan Chase & Co.

October 2021 - Present

Software Engineer

confidential

Netcare Access

November 2020 - April 2021

Mobile Crisis Clinician Columbus, OH

• The Mobile Crisis Response Unit is a combined effort of Netcare Access and the Columbus Division of Police. A Netcare clinician is paired with one Columbus police officer. Together, they respond to behavioral health and domestic disturbance calls in the community.

Sun Behavioral Health Hospital

July 2020 - January 2021

Intake Coordinator Columbus, OH

- Conduct psychiatric diagnosis intake assessment and coordinate services as appropriate to the recommended level of care and medical necessity evaluation.
- Complete verification of benefits and prior authorization review with managed care plan/third party payers.

Ensures appropriate screening of medical and behavioral emergency conditions.

Molina Healthcare Inc.

May 2016 - May 2020

Health Care Manager - Behavioral Team Lead Columbus, OH

conduct ongoing telephonic outreach aimed to reduce unnecessary high risk/high cost medical and/or behavioral health IP
 LOC/ED utilization through the implementation of motivational interviewing technique, providing ongoing preventative care education, and by addressing transition of care access, pharmaceutical and other self-care barriers identified.

Dublin Springs Hospital

October 2013 - May 2016

Utilization Review Specialist Dublin, OH

- Conducted initial and ongoing prior and concurrent live telephonic review requests on behalf of patient medical necessity determination and recommended levels of care authorization.
- Display knowledge of clinical pertinence, managed care requirements for in and outpatient authorization and advocate on behalf of the patient to secure coverage for needed services.
- Monitor, schedule and report status of peer to peer, and/or expedited appeal denials with the attending physician.
- Assist clinical treatment team with understanding levels of care criteria, and monitor justification for continuation of care.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

North Central Community Services

October 2012 - October 2013

Licensed Professional Counselor Columbus, OH

Miami Valley Hospital

June 2010 - August 2012

Graduate Research Assistant, Assistant Investigator Dayton, OH

United States Marine Corps Reserve

January 2006 - January 2013

Enlisted Infantry Rifleman (MOS 0311) Parris Island, SC Camp Geiger, NC Columbus, OH

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

We Can Code IT August 2021

Certificate of Software Development Columbus, OH

Wright State University

Masters of Science, Clinical Mental Health Counseling Dayton, OH

- Ohio Licensed Professional Counselor (LPC) License # C.110529
- The National Honor Society of Pi Lambda Theta

Wright State University

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology Dayton, OH

PUBLICATIONS

https://corescholar.libraries.wright.edu/surg/593/

In this prospective pilot evaluation of computerized driving simulation, adolescents subjected to structured simulator training showed trends toward committing fewer offenses and accidents. Larger studies examining the practical potential of driving simulation in novice drivers are needed. LEVEL OF EVIDENCE: Prognostic study, level III.